

Luke Wong Zhi Kiang

Junior Web Developer

+6017-3696453

▼ github.com/lukewzk

in linkedin.com/in/luke-wzk

PROFILE

Dedicated professional with 3 years of experience in the engineering field, specialising in the commissioning and maintenance of various bio-diesel and palm oil mill plants in Malaysia. I am currently seeking a job opportunity in web development and will use my experience, skills, and expertise to contribute to the management team at your company if given the opportunity.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Microsoft Excel	•	•	•	•	•
AutoCAD	•	•	•	•	•
CSS3	•	•	•	•	
ReactJS	•	•			•
Python	•	•			•

EDUCATION

NEXT Academy, *Quantum Degree* 2019 – 2019 | Malaysia

University of Birmingham, *MEng* (Hons) Chemical Engineering 2014 – 2016 | United Kingdom

Taylors University Lakeside, MEng (Hons) Chemical Engineering 2012 – 2014 | Malaysia

REFERRALS

Liren Yeo, *Mentor*, NEXT Academy 019-8891231

Nicholas Ong, *Mentor*, NEXT Academy 012-5290166

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

FoodyMoody App, Final Project at NEXT Academy

• **Facilitated** the front-end development of the "FoodyMoody" app which is aimed to reduce the time taken for users to decide on a place to eat, while **increasing daily productivity**.

Nextagram, *Project at NEXT Academy*

 Replicated Instagram by utilising ReactJS in 1 week. Built a fully functioning back-end server using Python and Flask (as a framework) for "Nextagram" which enabled users to sign up and store their data.

Noble Carbon Capture Unit, Bi-annual Engineering Design Fair

• Designed a carbon capture unit that is capable of absorbing harmful carbon monoxide gas from vehicles.

Chemical Powered Race Car, Bi-annual Engineering Fair

• **Designed** a car that is **powered by a chemical reaction** to run a certain set distance.

Multipurpose Baby Stroller, Bi-annual Engineering Fair

• **Designed** a baby stroller that can **maneuver up escalators** and steps.

Solar Powered Race Boat, Bi-annual Engineering Fair

• **Designed and constructed** a fully functional race boat to be **fully powered by solar energy** which **won second place** in the race.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

NEXT Academy, Student

07/2019 - 09/2019

• **Spearheaded** the creation of over **7 web apps** including a Tic-Tac-Toe Game, "Elusive Button Challenge", To-do List, Random GIF Generator, and a Live Message Board.

Lipochem Bio-tech Sdn. Bhd., *Project Engineer* 10/2017 – 07/2019

- **Represented and assisted** the company in the commissioning and construction of a multipurpose pilot plant for Sime Darby which helped to **generate income** for the company.
- Assisted in the pre-commissioning phase of a bio-diesel plant for Wilmar Group (Indonesia) which helped ensured the smooth operation of the commissioning phase later.
- **Commissioned** a crude palm oil (CPO) washing plant for Gan Teng Siew Realty Sdn. Bhd.

Rovski Sdn. Bhd., *Product Development Engineer* 10/2016 – 10/2017

- **Developed a new type of product** (butyl tape) for the company which helped **gained sales and revenue** for the company.
- Implemented working practices such as 5S & Kaizen daily which helped improve the overall working quality/condition of the company and department.